

1340 rue Olier, app 513 Montréal QC H3C 0P9

T 514 518 3830

jacob@peakwinter.net www.peakwinter.net

github.com/peakwinter twitter.com/peakwinter

Profile

I'm a **full-stack web developer**, passionate about creating quality software with a purpose. I've gained a great deal of experience while working in **app and website development** for several years now, both in **open source** and for commercial clients. In all of the work I do, I take the **initiative** and do my best to give that extra 'kick', turning a run-of-the-mill project into an extraordinary example, and constantly looking to give a **professional touch** to even the smallest of details. In my free time, I enjoy listening to music, spending time with friends, working on personal projects, **speaking at conferences** and writing about software development on my blog.

Skills

Backend: Python (Django, Flask), JavaScript (Node.js, Ember.js), API Design

Frontend: Ember.js, React, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Webpack, Gulp

**DevOps**: Docker, Ansible, Docker Swarm

Databases: PostgreSQL, MariaDB / MySQL, MongoDB

**Servers**: Systems Administration, DigitalOcean, AWS, Linode, Microsoft Azure, OVH **General**: Project and People Management, Agile / TDD, Sales Estimates, Calls for Tender

Experience

## **Project Director and Free Software Consultant**

Savoir-faire Linux, Montréal QC - Mar 2017 to present

Leading development work, project management and methodology for Django and DevOps projects. Crafting technical proposals and estimates for opportunities and calls for tender. Handling client communication and relationships. Teaching training courses in software development and programming languages to colleagues and clients.

#### **Freelance Software Developer**

Coderouge LLC - Jan 2014 to present

Providing freelance consulting services to companies and individuals on a variety of projects, centred around front-end development, web application backend/API engineering, geospatial database work, systems administration, infrastructure deployment and maintenance.

# **Project Leader and Software Developer**

CitizenWeb - Jan 2013 to Dec 2016

Managing development, hosting and deployment of open-source privacy and security projects. Overseeing a significant base of infrastructure (hosting servers and CDN). Creating the arkOS software and operating system that allows users to easily manage their data and web presence online from the comfort of their own home, while ensuring their privacy and data security. Created and oversaw solely a successful \$53,065 crowdfunding campaign in Fall 2013 with writeups about the project in VentureBeat, The New Yorker, Der Spiegel and many other publications.

# **Marketing and IT Services**

Haury's Lake City Collision, Seattle WA – Jul 2009 to Dec 2013

Managing a small corporate IT system of twenty users. Two Linux servers and ten Windows 7 workstations. Everything from fileshares to email, roaming user profiles to database application support. Maintaining a complex on-site network including router, switches and wireless access points. Creating and routinely updating the company website. Overseeing company marketing initiatives.

#### Projects

## **Sylow**

2016 to present — https://sylow.info

Sylow is a personal data store and exchange system, founded on principles of sharing and encryptability, upon which a wide variety of client applications can be built.

### arkOS

2013 to 2017 — https://github.com/arkOScloud

arkOS is a self-hosted application management platform and operating system, allowing for easy management of a home server through the use of an "app store" style interface.

### Education

### **BA Political Science, minor French Language**

Concordia University – 2011 to 2013

English	French
Native proficiency	Fluent proficiency (TÉFAQ score: C2 Comp., C2 Exp.)
Node.js Foundation	Python Software Foundation
Member — 2017 to present	Member — 2017 to present
	Native proficiency  Node.js Foundation

# **Linux Foundation**

Member — 2012 to present